you have finally understood smart money
Concepts after watching this video so in
this video I want to simplify smart
money Concepts in a way that even a
5-year-old kid can understand most of
the information that you can find online
is all about retail trading oh buy and
support level if you search for how
smart money and the big Banks trade you
won't find much information about it and
today smart money trading is probably
one of the best kept secrets in in the
world of trading and today I want to
review those secrets with you I mean to
you once you learn how smart money
trades you can implement this Concepts
into your style of trading and make even
more money so let me explain to you some
smart money Concepts that you must
follow so that you can finally become a
profitable Trader so firstly let's talk
about boss or break off structure so in
an uptrend price will be looking like
this you'll be making your higher highs
and higher lows every time price breaks
through a new high this is what we call
a bullish break of structure or B boss
so there's a break of structure here
there's another break of structure right
here and another break of structure
right here whenever price breaks the
previous high so at some point of time
price will eventually lose momentum and
start reversing in the other direction
and for this reversal to be valid price
has to break the pre previous higher low
so this is the previous higher low and
price has to break below it for it to be
valid so once this move has happened
this is what we call the chalk or rather
a change of character Chalk in order for
this chalk to work we want this previous
High to be an area of Interest like
either a supply or demand zone or an
order block so the stronger the Zone the
better it is right the better this chalk
will works once we have a change of
character the chalk and an area of
Interest your supply Zone we can expect
price to reverse and start going down
and then as it starts to go down it will
create your lower highs and lower lows
and lower highs and lower lows and as
price creates your lower highs and lower
lows it will also create your bearish
break of structure whenever price break
through a lower low so when price break
to a low low it creates another break of
structure right here so this is our
bullish break of structure and this is
our bearish break of structure and this
is our change of character and at some
point of time this downtrend will start
losing momentum like this uptrend right
here and it will start reversing back up
and this will create your change of
character right here so this is pretty
much the whole concept of this smart
money Concepts break of structure and
change of character for this strategy to
work we want the area of Interest
interest this zone right here this
supply and demand Zone to be as strong
as possible because the stronger it is
the more likely the price will move in
the direction that you want it to now
what do I mean by strong area of
interest there are two methods that you
can use the first method is what we call
the liquidity grap at a supply or demand
Zone firstly you need to identify a
strong Supply or demand Zone on the
higher time frame like the 1 hour time
frame or above so the higher the time
frame the stronger the area will be and
what you want price to do is your
liquidity grab so what is a liquidity
grab a liquidity grab is basically a FSE
breakout right in this case where price
breaks through a recent high or low does
a fake out like this and then reverses
in the opposite direction so the
psychology behind this liquidity grab is
that people will be entering for a sell
when price breaks through the recent low
because this is the recent low and when
price breaks through the recent low the
sellers will be selling down because
they think that this is a downtrend
right so when they enter for a sell
right here they're going to be placing
their stop loss above the last lower
high which is right here so if price end
up doing a force breakout and price
actually comes up it will hit all their
stop losses adding fuel to the fire and
increasing the momentum causing price to
shoot up so we can take advantage of
this by entering for a buy position
somewhere right around here and make
money as price goes to the moon the
second method to find a key area of
interest is by using order blocks so an
order block is basically an area where
the smart money and Big Bangs likes to
enter and exit so how do you spot order
blocks you spot order blocks by looking
for strong reversals like this and this
and this you can see whenever price goes
up here here it reverse down strongly
and when price come back down here it
reverse back up strongly so this level
right here and this level right here is
what we call the order blocks now let's
combine whatever that we just learned
and I'm going to show you a high win
rate smart money trading strategy so for
this strategy make sure that you are
using a higher time frame like the 1
hour time frame the first thing before
you do anything is that you want to mark
up your key levels or supply and demand
zones by finding where price is
reversing or respecting right here
whenever price goes up here it always
collapse one time two time three times
four times so this is a very strong
Supply Zone and I can draw another
demand Zone at this key support era
right here so now I'm going to show you
this strategy on gbpusd the Great
British pound against the US dollar we
can see that there's a support area
right around this area here because
whenever price come back down here it
always reversal come back down reverses
so you can see price has just been
respecting this support level or demand
Zone whatever you like to call it and
over here price gave us a liquidity GP
so the first thing you want to look for
is for price to give us a liquidity grap
or a fce breakout at a supply or demand
Zone which is exactly what price gave us
here price broke through the support
level and then it just went back up so
this was a very clear Force breakout or
what I like to call liquidity grap now
you can mark up your break of structure
here and the next thing you want to look
for is a change of corrector price must
make a change of character after the
liquidity grap do not take that trade if
there is no change of character so it's
very very important they will look out
for a change of character after the
liquidity grab so I can spot a change of
character right here because this is the
last lower high before price collaps and
then at this point of time this is when
price has broken the last lower high
breaking structure causing a change of
character now next when do we actually
enter for the trade we enter when there
is a fair value Gap now what is a fair
value Gap a fair value Gap is when price
goes up or down so fast that it doesn't
give buyers or sellers enough time to
enter the market therefore it creates an
imbalance in the market so price will
usually come back up or come back down
to this fair value Gap and reject it and
that is when you can enter for the trade
so you can Mark a fair value Gap by
using a rectangular tool to Mark the
previous candles week before the big
move and then taking the next candle
week after the big move so right here
this would be your fair value Gap so
there are bullish fair value gap which
is basically a big fat green candle and
there is also bearish fair value Gap
like this big red candle right here so
back to the example you want to enter
for a buy when price has came back down
to our fair value Gap so in this example
I can spot a fair value Gap right here
you can see right here there's a fair
value Gap and right now what we want to
do is to wait for price to come back
down to retest this fair value Gap then
that is when we can enter for a buy and
the reason why I mark this as the fair
value Gap is that if you look towards
right here at this candle here price
went up super fast right went up super
fast gave us a big fat green candle this
Candlestick week the next Candlestick
week and the Candlestick week before it
I marked up the entire box giving us the
fair value Gap so I want you to know
that price can come to the midle of the
fair value Gap reject it and then
continue going up but at the same time
remember price can do anything it wants
so price can also touches the fair value
gap which is like this area here just
touches it and just reverse and head
back up so if you were waiting for the
price to go to the midle you have missed
out on the trade so ultimately it's
really up to you on which way you want
to do it right there is no right or
wrong answer so in this trade I have
entered for a buy right here when price
has came to the middle of this fair
value Gap and it's showing me some sort
of signs that it's going to reject it
and hit back up and I'll place my stop
loss below the fair value Gap and I'll
place my thck profit at where price last
stop at if you look towards the left
there a little resistance area being
formed right around this area here so
that is where I should place my take
profit and as you can see this was a one
is three R to the ratio trade very very
beautiful trade and the thing about
trading fair value gaps is that you are
able to get those nice sniper entries
which will give you a high risk to
reward ratio this trade smash our take
profit right here very very beautiful
trade and the next thing I'm looking for
is another trade so to show you this
strategy works I'm just going to be
continue using this strategy on this
chart so let's wait wait and you can see
at this point of time price created
another resistance area or that's rather
a supply Zone and it gave us a liquidity
grap right here when price broke through
the resistance and then it came back
down so this was a fce breakout so this
is a liquidity grab and the next thing
you want to look for is a change of
character this is a change of character
right here because this is the last
higher low before price goes up and like
fa the break pass right so this was a
little change of corrector right here
price came back down broke through the
last higher low giving us a change of
corre so next thing I want to do is to
mark up my fair value Gap and I can mark
up a fair value Gap right here because I
saw there's a huge push down and there's
a big break candle here so I'll mark my
fair value Gap right here and you can
see price has went back up to retest the
fair value Gap so this is where I will
enter for a sell position and price is
came back up to retest this fair value
Gap enter in the middle of this fair
value Gap place your stop loss Above
This fair value Gap and take profit all
the way down at the next key level and I
can see there's a support level right
here I place my take profit right there
and once again this was a very very
beautiful trade we end up smashing our
take profit on this trade it's really
really as simple as that guys I know
that a lot of YouTubers a lot of people
on YouTube have been trying to make
smart money Concepts very complicated
very very hard to understand so that you
guys can buy the cost and I'm telling
you it's complicated but it's not that
complicated it's still doable all right
it's still doable and I'm here to help
to simplify this entire process because
I understand how you feel when I first
started learning about smart money
Concepts all these boss chalks BOS fair
value Gap all these foreign terms I have
no idea what the hell are those and then
I went to do my research and I end up
being even more confused than I already
am I hope that like this video was able
to like help to simplify it but do not
exit this video yet I'm going to show
you more examples because I understand a
lot of you guys still probably do not
understand this strategy yet and you
have to understand this strategy if you
want to trade smart money Concepts so
right here after we close this trade
once again price is at this support area
right here consolidating around this
area and there's a breakout structure
over here when price broke through the
last high right here and at this point
of time price went back up to the same
resistance area that we have drawn and
it gave us a liquidity grab once again
gave us a liquidity grab and then this
is the last lower low or last higher low
and right now price has broken this last
higher low so once price has broken this
last higher low it gave us a change of
corrector when price gave us a change of
corrector next step is to look for a
fair value Gap and I can see a fair
value Gap right here this big red candle
here and you can see but price went up
to retest it and if you notice price did
not go to the middle of this fair value
Gap and then go down it literally just
went up touched the fair value Gap and
go down so this is exactly what I mean
by what I said just now sometimes price
can just touch the fa Gap and then just
collapse so in this case if you were
waiting for price to go to the middle of
this fair value Gap and then go down you
would have missed out on this trade but
like I said ultimately it's still up to
you so I'm going to show you one last
example and you can see I've drawn some
break of structure and honestly break of
structure you can draw it on your charts
but Le strategy is more about change of
character so right now price has been
collapsing coming down to our beautiful
support area right here this beautiful
strong demand Zone price literally gave
us a huge liquidity GB right here Force
breakout huge liquidity grab so next
thing I to look for is a change of
character and I get a change of
character right here because this is
like the last high and price has broken
the last high right here so this was a
little change of corre and actually
within this move I can actually spot
another change of character somewhere
right around here because if you look
closely right this price was trying to
create a new like lower high and lower
low and lower high and lower low and if
fail to do that so price actually gave
us a l lower high high right here so the
moment price break through this last
lower high that would be your change of
character this thing is so damn long let
me just shorten this thing right here
put it right here the moment price start
breaking through this last lower high
this is the last lower high and price
broke through it this is a change of
character so right now I can spot a fair
value Gap right here and I'm waiting for
price to come back down to retest this
fair value gap which it did right here
so the moment price start coming down
here to back to this fair value Gap I'm
going to be entering for a buy right
here place my stop loss below this fair
value Gap place my take profit at the
next key level which is right here
there's a key level being form right
here right there's a resistance area so
you can see once again this was a very
very beautiful trade and really is all
about wins and repeating the same thing
right I have shown you that this
strategy works this chalk boss boss and
this strategy work all right I'm
going to call it boss and Cox strategy
from now on it's a very beautiful name
very easy to remember so make sure that
you go apply whatever you just learned
on the charts and integrate whatever you
just learned into practice because
that's the only way you can Master smart
money concepts by practicing endlessly
like this video If this video has helped
you guys out I really try my best to
simplify smart money Concepts which is a
super complicated concept to into a way
where like a 5-year-old can understand
so smash that like button and hit on
that subscribe button for more weekly
trading videos and if you want to learn
about how I trade using price action
check out this video right here trust me
this strategy is 10 times simpler than
the freaking smart money Trading
strategy all right click on this video
right here to find out more and remember
you're just one trade away